Lazybones.
الحشرة الكسولة
Get up. Hurry.
استيقظ بسرعة
I need to get some more sleep.
‫سأنام قليلا
Captain Lu's men are here.
‫جاء فريق لو
I haven't changed my clothes yet.
لم أغير ملابسي بعد
Look how nervous you are.
أنت متوترة
They're outside.
أين الباب؟
Isn't the flight tomorrow?
أليست طائرة الغد؟
I just
البارحة
called him yesterday.
اتصلت به أمس
Hello, Aunt Gui Xiao.
أهلا يا عمة جو شياو
Are you here alone?
‫هل أتيت بنفسك
Uncle Lu is downstairs.
‫العم لو في الطابق السفلي
Last night, Aunt Cai said
‫قالت العمة تساي الليلة الماضية
she would take the train
أنها ركبت القطار اليوم
to go abroad for business today.
للذهاب إلى الخارج للتجارة
My dad said he was off today.
قال أبي إنه يستريح اليوم
So he could send Aunt Cai off.
ليخرج العمة تساي
Yes, I did mention it.
أجل، لقد قلت
Thank you so much.
شكرا لكم
You're welcome.
لا بأس
Good morning.
صباح الخير
Morning, Captain Lu.
‫صباح الخير أيها القائد لو
Aunt Gui Xiao.
سيدة جوى شياو
Son.
بني
What time did you sleep last night?
كم الساعة نمت أمس
I didn't sleep.
لم أنم
When we are on duty,
عندما كنت في مهمة
it's normal not to sleep for a few days.
من الطبيعي عدم النوم لبضعة أيام
I'm used to it already.
لقد اعتدت
It's not easy for the country to train you guys.
ليس من السهل تربيتكم الدولة
You should take care of your health.
اعتني بصحتك
So that you can work for a few more years.
بهذه الطريقة يمكن أن تعمل لعدة سنوات
It's the border.
الحدود
Is the photo you sent to me
الصورة التي أرسلتها لي في البداية
taken here?
هل هي هنا
No.
لا
Later on,
في المستقبل
if you come to Qining again,
يمكنك القدوم إلى تشي نينغ مرة أخرى
I'll ask them to take you
سأجعلهم يأخذونك
to the place where the photo was taken.
إلى مكان لمشاهدة الصور
I don't know
المرة القادمة
when will be the next time.
لا أعرف متى
The view here is nice.
المناظر هنا جيدة
You should look more at
نهر جميل في البلاد
the beautiful rivers and mountains of our motherland.
يجب أن نرى أكثر
You've lived here for more than ten years.
لقد عشت هنا لأكثر من عشر سنوات
I suppose
ربما
it feels like looking at your hometown.
يشبه مشاهدة مسقط رأسه
Captain Qin said
قال الرئيس تشين
he would help me watch over my car for a week
ساعدني في التحقق من السيارة لمدة أسبوع
until I returned.
انتظرني
It's very nice of him.
شخص جيد
Captain Qin, thanks.
شكرا أيها الرئيس تشين
Don't mention it. We're friends.
على الرحب والسعة نحن أصدقاء
Thank you.
شكرا
You may go through the customs and take the train from there.
‫أخرج من هناك إلى الجمارك ركب القطار
Captain Lu,
‫أيها القائد لو
once again, I would like to express
سأعبر لك مرة أخرى
my sincere gratitude to you.
شكرا لك بصدق
I'll treat you to a meal when I get back to Beijing.
سأدعوك لتناول العشاء عندما نعود إلى بكين
Captain Lu, see you again.
‫أيها القائد لو، أراك لاحقاً
Bye.
مع السلامة
Okay, you can go now.
حسناً اذن اذهبا
Take care.
انتبهوا على الطريق
Have a safe trip.
رحلة آمنة
Okay.
حسنا
Bye.
مع السلامة
Aunt.
عمتي
Why don't you
لماذا
go abroad with them?
لم تخرج خارج الحدود معهم
I have work to do in Beijing.
العمة لديها عمل في بكين
I need to go back to Beijing.
سأعود إلى بكين
The three of them came to Qining
إنهم الثلاثة يأتون إلى تشي نينغ
for foreign trade.
من أجل التجارة الخارجية
Aunt, why are you here?
‫لماذا أتيت يا عمتي
Are you coming specially for Uncle Lu?
‫هل من أجل العم لو؟
No.
‫لا
How could it be?
كيف يمكن ذلك؟
Xiaonan, if you keep talking nonsense,
شياو نان ، إذا استمررت في التحدث بالهراء
Aunt won't take you with her anymore.
لن آخذكِ معي
Lu.
‫لو،
I've got an emergency mission.
‫مهمة عاجلة
I'll leave them to you.
سأتركهما لك
Go ahead.
اذهبي
Xiaonan, be obedient to Aunt.
شياو نان استمعي إلي
Thank you.
شكراً
Aunt, are you free after this?
عمتي هل أنت بخير بعد قليل
Yes, I am.
أنا بخير
Can you help me pack up my luggage?
هل يمكنك مساعدتي في حزم أمتعتي؟
Why can't you do it yourself?
لماذا لا يمكنك أن تأخذها بنفسك
What do you
ما الشيء
need help with from others?
تحتاج إلى مساعدة الآخرين
None of us can.
لا يمكننا فعل ذلك
Men are not careful enough.
الرجال غير حذرين
We'll leave something out.
سيسرب شيء بالتأكيد
Okay.
حسنا
Thank you.
شكرا
Does he live alone?
هل يعيش بمفرده عادةً؟
When his dad comes,
عندما عاد والده
he makes the bed up there
رتبوا الطابق العلوي
and sleeps on the upper bunk.
اسكن في السرير العلوي
Why doesn't he apply for a dorm,
لماذا لا تقدم بطلب للسكن
taking his son together?
خذه معك
In our profession,
في مهنتنا
once there is a mission,
إذا كان لدينا مهمة حقا
our working hours will be uncertain.
ليس لدينا وقت العمل
If the kid stays in the dorm,
أخشى أن يسكن الطفل في السكن
first, his resting will be disturbed.
الأول هو إزعاج العمل والراحة
Second, seeing his dad often goes out,
ثانيًا، رأيت والده يخرج كثيرًا
he'll be worried.
يقلق كثيرا
Kids nowadays are smart.
الأطفال الآن ذكيون
He knows his dad's profession.
يعرف ماذا يفعل والده
He'll be worried anyway.
لا يقلق بشأن التصوير
Besides,
والآن
there're numerous movies about explosive ordnance disposal nowadays.
العديد من الأفلام
Doesn't he
لقد شاهد
ask you guys after watching them?
ألا يشعرون بالفضول؟
Usually, we would say that
عادة أجيبنا
the movie scenes are all made-up.
‫في الأفلام كلها كذبة‬
It's not that dangerous.
ليس بهذه الخطورة
So it's all true.
كل شيء حقيقي
It's dangerous, isn't it?
خطير جدا أليس كذلك
Can't you even tell your friends?
ألا يمكن أن يقول الأصدقاء
Every profession has difficulty.
ليس من السهل أن يكون هناك مهنة
There's nothing to say.
لا يوجد شيء لأقوله
Is this all?
هذا كل شيء
Doesn't his father
!حضرة اللورد
buy him clothes?
ألا يشتري له ملابس؟
Also, why doesn't
بالإضافة إلى استئجار منزل
he rent
لماذا لا تستأجر
a more spacious house?
أكبر
Isn't it too small
هذا الرجل يعيش هنا
for them to live here?
هل هو صغير جدا
Are they your parents?
‫والداك
It's Uncle Lu and...
‫العم لو
Maybe
‫ربما
his alumnus.
زميله في المدرسة
Why can't I understand
لماذا لم أفهم
Captain Lu is here.
‫جاء فريق لو
I have to say hello to him.
دعني ألقي التحية
They're developing feelings for each other.
إنهم يتدربون على المشاعر
Are they helping you pack
إنهم يساعدونك في حزم أمتعتك
and move?
لمساعدتك على الانتقال
Thank you
في هذه السنوات
for taking care of me all this time.
أشكرك على رعايتك
Why did you close the door?
لماذا أغلقت الباب
The kid outside will get it wrong.
لقد أساء فهم الأطفال في الخارج
We can talk conveniently if the door is closed.
أغلق الباب
His parents are divorced.
‫لقد طلق والديه‬
Qin Mingyu got his son.
‫تشين مينغيو حصل على ابنه‬
But deep down,
لكن في قلبه يعتقد
he felt that he had dragged on Xiaonan's mother,
أن أمه قد تأخرت
so he paid her a lot of money.
دفعت الكثير من المال للطرف الآخر
I see.
هكذا
Now he has to take care of his parents
والديه بالتبني الآن
and raise his son.
ويجب تربية ابنه
So he doesn't dare to spend money freely.
لا أجرؤ على إنفاق المال
I've done packing the clothes.
لقد رتبت الملابس
I'll leave the books for you to pack since you're more familiar with them.
‫أنت تعرف الكتب فلترتبي‬
I'll go out first.
سأذهب الآن
My dad said...
قال أبي
My dad said that
قال أبي أنه
he was not coming back for dinner tonight.
لن يعود لتناول الطعام
I got it.
فهمت
Let me see.
دعني أرى
It's okay.
لا بأس لا بأس
I'll go out first.
سأذهب الآن
Otherwise, the kid will misunderstand.
خلاف ذلك سوف يسيء الفهم
Get out.
اخرج
This is even more misunderstanding.
هذا أسوء الفهم
Remember to take
تذكري أن تأخذي
Qin Xiaonan's household registration permit
دفتر تسجيل تشين شياو نان
for boarding purposes.
تستخدم الصعود على الطائرة
Stay in the car.
ابقي في السيارة
I need to talk to your aunt.
أريد التحدث مع العمة
He doesn't have a household registration permit.
ليس لديه سجل الأسرة
He doesn't?
لا
His household registration permit
تسجيل عائلته
has been with his mother.
ظل في منزل والدته
After the divorce,
بعد الطلاق
his mother always hopes
كانت والدته تتمنى
Xiaonan can live with her.
أن تذهب شياو نان معها
Although the court has made a judgment,
على الرغم من حكم المحكمة
these two
لكن هذان الشخصان
have been dilly-dallying regarding household registration.
‫يستمر في التسجيل‬
Qin Mingyu is also busy
‫تشين مينغيو مشغول أيضا‬
that he has no time to do it.
‫لم يكن لدي وقت للقيام به‬
Then, what should we do?
ماذا علينا أن نفعل؟
Does he have a passport?
هل لديك جواز سفري
Yes.
نعم
Give me his passport first.
أعطني جواز سفرك أولا
We'll discuss it after flying to Beijing.
سنذهب إلى بكين أولاً
But we need
لكن الدراسة
both the original and photocopy
تحتاج أصل تسجيل الأسرة
of his household registration permit.
والنسخ
The school will need to verify them.
المدرسة تحتاج إلى إلقاء نظرة
We'll figure this out this month.
سنفكر في طريقة هذا الشهر
Poor kid.
هذا الطفل مثير للشفقة
Passport.
جواز سفري
I'll go back to Beijing after the Chinese New Year.
سأعود إلى بكين بعد العام الجديد
It's almost time.
تقريبا
You may go in.
‫ادخل
Goodbye, Uncle Lu.
‫مع السلامة العم لو
Alright.
‫حسناً
It's not like we'll never see each other again.
ليس مفقود
We'll get going then.
سنذهب الآن
Why didn't your dad come to see you off?
لماذا لم يأتي والدك لتوصلك
He hasn't been home for two days.
لم يعد إلى المنزل هذه الأيام
He only called once.
فقط اتصل به
It's okay.
لا بأس
You can visit him during the summer break.
عندما أعود لزيارته في العطلة الصيفية
I may not able to see him
عندما نعود
even if I go back.
قد لا نراه
Last year when I just arrived at Qining,
لقد وصلت للتو إلى تشي نينغ العام الماضي
my dad was on a mission,
أبي لديه مهمة
a confidential one.
سر
I couldn't see him for days.
لم أره منذ عدة أيام
Then,
إذًا
what about you?
ماذا ستفعل؟
Was there no one who took care of you?
لا أحد يعتني به
Yes.
نعم
The family of other team members took turns taking care of me.
‫عائلتنا تعتني بي بشكل متناوب‬
But I cried every night.
أنا أبكي كل ليلة
I thought my dad had abandoned me.
ظننت أن أبي لا يريدني
Let me tell you.
أقول لك
I even cried
عندما كانت الخالة جو شياو في المدرسة الثانوية
when I was in high school.
كانت تبكي
My parents were divorcing at that time.
عندما طلق والداي
So I cried a lot.
كان يبكي دائما
You are so melodramatic.
‫أنت عنيد جدا‬
What's wrong with you?
لماذا أنت هكذا
I was trying to comfort you.
أنا أواسيك بلطف
My dad said that I couldn't lie,
قال أبي لا يمكن الكذب
especially to you.
خاصة لك
So I was being honest with you.
لذلك أقول الحقيقة
I won't argue with you.
لن أتشاجر معك
I'll take you hanging out tomorrow.
سآخذك للعب غدا
Where do you want to go?
إلى أين تريد أن تذهب؟
The Palace Museum, the Temple of Heaven
القصر الملكي   القاعة السماوية
or the Great Wall?
أو مدينة طويلة
How about this?
هكذا
I'll take you
سآخذك
to visit
لنتجول
all the famous tourist spots
في كل مكان
before we go to the local spots.
سآخذك لمس مكان صغير
I don't want to go anywhere.
لا أريد الذهاب إلى أي مكان
We don't spend your dad's money.
لا أنفق أموال والدك
Your money is also money.
أموالك أيضا
That's Xinhe Hospital.
هذا هو شين والمستشفى
Do you know it?
هل تعرف
I know.
أعرف
I used to go there when I was young.
كنت أذهب إلى هناك كثيرًا عندما كنت صغيرًا
And there's also a 341 Hospital.
هناك واحد آخر
Is it nearby?
هل هو قريب؟
I know it too.
أعرف أيضا
You know a lot.
‫أنت تعرف الكثير
Uncle Lu told me.
‫أخبرني العم لو
He said
‫قال
he went to 341 Hospital
ذهب إلى ثلاثة أربعة واحد
to visit a friend.
لرؤية صديق
A hospitalized friend.
صديق في المستشفى
Is it you?
إنه أنت
Maybe.
ربما
What do you mean by maybe?
ماذا تعني ربما
I can't remember.
لا أتذكر بوضوح
We are arriving at my home.
منزلي على وشك الوصول
That is the place you are going to stay
هذا هو المكان
for the next month.
في الشهر المقبل
Come in.
ادخل
This is the house I rent.
هذا المنزل الذي استأجرته
You can look around later.
انظر ببطء بعد قليل
Come and change your shoes.
تعال لتغيير الحذاء
Put them on.
ارتدي هذا
I can't help you manage the suitcase today.
لا أستطيع حمل الصندوق اليوم
Take out your pyjamas.
أخرجي ملابس النوم
I'll take you upstairs to take a shower and go to bed.
سآخذك إلى الطابق العلوي للاستحمام والنوم
I usually
أنا عادة
sleep naked.
أنام عاريا
You have to wear clothes here.
عليك ارتداء الملابس هنا
I'm a girl.
أنا فتاة
We should respect each other.
يجب أن نحترم بعضنا البعض
Okay.
حسنا
I'm not familiar with this place.
أنا لست على دراية بهذا المكان
Can you buy it for me tomorrow?
اشتري لي غدا
Okay, leave it to me.
حسنًا، سأتولى الأمر
Thanks.
شكرا
You finally came back.
أخيراً عدت
Didn't you be tied
لم يتم حبسها
by the beautiful mountains and rivers of our motherland?
على جبل البلاد
Did anything happen
قبل سنة شركتنا
before the Chinese New Year?
هل حدث شيء كبير
No.
لا
It's almost New Year. Everyone is lazy.
السنة الجديدة قريبًا، الجميع كسول
That's good.
هذا جيد
By the way,
صحيح
there's a kid at my house.
لدينا طفل الآن
He's the child of my friend.
ولد صديقي قادم
So I won't work overtime.
لذلك لا أعمل لساعات إضافية
If there are any needs,
إذا كان لديك أي عمل
I'll work from home.
سآخذه إلى العمل
I'm fine with it.
لا مشكلة
I'm not the boss.
أنا لست الرئيس
The boss is coming.
من سيأتي
You're back.
لقد عدت
Tomorrow is Laba.
غداً لابا
I was worried
كنت قلقة عليك من قبل
you wouldn't be able to catch up with the congee from Yonghe Palace.
أنك لن تلحق عصيدة عيد الربيع لقصر يونغ خه
Perfect.
بالضبط
Oh yeah.
صحيح
I almost forgot.
لقد نسيت إذا لم تخبرني
Are we going together tomorrow
لنذهب معا غدا
or I queue up for you first?
دعني أساعدك في اصطف أولا
No need.
لا داعي
I'll take someone there.
سآخذ شخص
Her friend's kid
طفلها في منزل صديقتها
will stay at her house until the Chinese New Year.
‫يسكن في منزلهم قبل السنة الجديدة
Okay.
حسنًا
Qin Xiaonan.
تشين شياو نان
-Qin... -Coming.
تشين آتي
Slow down. Be careful not to fall.
تمهل لا تسقط
You've underestimated me.
أنت تقلل من شأني
These stairs
هذه السلالم
won't hurt me.
لا يمكن أن تسقط
Why didn't you turn on the lights?
لماذا لا تشغل الضوء
It was dark when I came in.
عندما دخلت الظلام
You scared me.
لقد أخفتني
I thought something happened to you.
ظننت أنك تعرضت لحادث
It's on.
إنه مفتوح
I've turned on the desk lamp.
أنا أفتح المصباح
Your lights are too bright.
ضوئك ساطع للغاية
It must consume a lot of electricity.
من الواضح أن الكهرباء ينفق
I was not in the living room.
أنا لست في غرفة المعيشة
so I switched off all of them.
لذلك أغلقتها
Come here.
تعال
Women like shopping.
النساء يحبون التسوق
These are all for you.
اشتريتها لك
Heartless boy.
أنت عديم الضمير
I don't have that much money for you.
ليس لدي الكثير من المال لأعطيك
They are at a 90% discount.
هذه خصم
All are on sale.
كلها سعر خاص
I spent all the money
لقد أنفقت كل المال
you gave me to buy these.
لقد أنفقت كل ما اشتريته
And I have points
لدي نقاط إضافية
to redeem the gifts for free.
يمكن تغيير مجانا
Points?
نقاط
You can redeem so many things?
يمكنك تغيير الكثير من الأشياء
Of course.
ممكن
I bought a lot in the past.
اشتريت الكثير في الماضي
So I got many points.
بالطبع هناك الكثير من النقاط
You lied to me.
أنت تكذب علي
You money-grubber.
‫فتاة ثرية
You still have your wallet with you.
لا يزال يحمل المحفظة معك
What do you want for dinner?
ماذا تريدين أن تأكلي في المساء
I'll order takeout.
سأطلب الطعام
You are leaving one week earlier
أغادر مبكرا
than planned.
قبل أسبوع
Are you anxious to return home?
هل تريد العودة كالسهم
Your son is in Beijing.
ابنك في بكين
Aren't you worried?
ألا تقلق
He is with Gui Xiao.
عندما يعود
It's better than with you.
أفضل من البقاء معك
Give this to Gui Xiao.
أعطي جوا شياو
It's for Xiaonan's living expenses.
رسوم حياة شياو نان
Where did you get the money?
من أين حصلت على المال؟
It's my bonus.
جائزة
Gui Xiao bought not only clothes
لقد عاد إلى شياو نان
but also books for Xiaonan.
لشراء الملابس والكتاب
Right? She provides food and accommodation.
أليس كذلك
We can't pretend to be unaware of it.
لا يمكننا أن نتظاهر بأننا لا نعرف
Also,
وأيضا
most importantly,
أهم شيء
she introduced me to a school.
قدموا لي المدرسة
A school?
المدرسة
This helped me a lot.
لقد ساعدتني كثيرا
She has done me a huge favour.
هذا معروف كبير
Favour is the most valuable, do you know that?
‫المعروف هي الأكثر قيمة
Take it.
خذ
I will pay her.
سأعطيها
You should keep your bonus to celebrate the New Year with your family.
أعطي المكافأة للمنزل للاحتفال بعيد الربيع
What do you mean
‫أعطني المال يا ابني
by paying for my son?
ما الذي يجري؟
It's on your account.
سجلي الحساب أولا
When you become rich,
بعد أن تتطور
pay me triple.
ثلاثة أضعاف
Okay.
‫حسناً
Captain Lu.
‫أيها القائد لو
I might come back in the future.
ربما سيعود
You'd better not come back.
من الأفضل ألا تعود
It's not easy for you to transfer back there.
لقد عدت أخيراً
You should make up with
أسرع
our ex-sister-in-law.
للعودة
You're over 30 years old
لقد كان عمره أكثر من ثلاثين سنة
but you still care about your pride.
لا تزال تحترم ماء وجهك
If you like her, just go for it.
إذا أعجبتك
Shut up.
اخرس
I'm leaving.
سأذهب
Take a leave as soon as possible
اطلب إجازة بسرعة
and get the household registration permit back.
أحضر دفتر تسجيل الأسرة
I remember that.
أتذكر
You're finally back.
لقد عدت أخيرا
Why didn't you inform me?
لماذا لم تخبرني
I would pick you up.
سآخذك
Let me see.
دعني أرى
The campus beau in those days
ما زال رائعاً
is still so handsome.
لا يزال وسيماً
Screw you!
تبا لك
Let's go.
هيا بنا
Go home.
لنعود للمنزل
I've booked
لقد حجزت لك الليلة
the fanciest restaurant next to our house
أكبر فندق بجانب منزلنا
to welcome you.
للترحيب بك
I don't have time to eat with you.
ليس لدي وقت لتناول العشاء معك
My mum is sick.
أمي مريضة
I came back
سأعود
to pack a change of clothes
سأحضر بعض الملابس لتغييرها
before I go to the hospital.
يجب أن أذهب إلى المستشفى
Your mum is sick?
عمتي مريضة
It's my fault.
هذا خطأي
I've been doing business
منذ فترة
outside.
كنت أعمل في الخارج
So I haven't had a chance to visit your mum.
لم أذهب إلى منزلك لزيارة أمي أنا
Meng Xiaoshan.
‫منغ شياو شان‬
Cancel the table
لقد حجزت تلك الطاولة الليلة
I reserved for tonight.
ألغيها
I'm not going.
لدي شيء لا أذهب
My younger brother
أخي هنا
is dealing with the school application for Xiaonan.
في منزلي
Have you got his household registration permit
هل حصلت
and birth certificate?
هل حصلت عليه؟
Don't worry.
لا تقلق
I'll be there next time.
سأذهب في يوم آخر
I haven't got them yet.
لم أحصل عليه بعد
Sorry, I'll be quick.
آسف، سأبذل قصارى جهدي
Not yet.
ليس بعد
Let's make up for it later.
إذًا الإدارة
Since it's confirmed,
على أي حال تم تحديد الأمر
I'll hold off for you with my guarantee.
سأحفظ ماء وجهي لك أولا
Thanks.
شكرا
What's wrong with you?
ما خطبك؟
How many donations
أختي في البداية
has Sister made for us
في البداية
for the mountainous area?
إلى المنطقة الجبلية
Without her,
لولا أختي
would you have connected with so many prestigious schools?
أنت تعرف الكثير من الأكاديمية الجيدة
Guarantee?
كيف تجرؤ
Your guarantee is valid because of Sister.
ألم تعطيك وجه الأخت
Yes.
نعم
Don't bother him, Sister.
تجاهله يا أختي
Well,
حسناً
as for the procedures afterwards,
ما الإجراءات التي تحتاجها بعد ذلك
make a list for me.
قومي بتسجيل قائمة لي
I'll finish them during the winter break.
سأستغل إجازة الشتاء
I'll give it to you tomorrow.
سأعطيك غدًا
Okay.
حسنا
I'll get it for you, Uncle.
سأصبه يا عمي
Good boy.
مطيعة جدا
You've been to the north
قلت أنك ذهبت إلى الشمال للاسترخاء
for less than a week,
ليس أسبوع
but you took back
فقط أحضرت
a kid you didn't know before.
لم أقابله من قبل
Not only are you
لحل المشكلة
helping with his education,
لا نتحدث عن مشاكل الدراسة
but you also filled in his regular address as your home.
‫لقد ملأ عنوانها
Sister, if you weren't a woman
أختي لو لم تكوني فتاة
and couldn't satisfy the condition,
لا يمكننا أن نرضي قدرتنا الأساسية
I would have thought that
اعتقدت حقا أن هذا الطفل
he was
أنت من تركته في الخارج
your illegitimate child.
أين ابنك غير شرعي
You're right.
لا تقل إنه يشبه حقا
Right?
أليس كذلك
Let's have dinner together tonight.
لنتناول العشاء معا
I'll book a restaurant.
سأحجز مطعم
Don't bother, Sister. You're always so generous.
لا يا أختي   دائما ما أجعلك تكلفين المال
Can't I take the kid
أريد أن آخذ الأطفال لتناول اللحم
to have some meat?
لا يمكن
Go. Put on your down jacket.
اذهب، اخلع سترة
The one I bought for you.
‫الذي اشتريته لك‬
How about this?
هكذا
We'll go downstairs and wait in the car.
لنذهب إلى الطابق السفلي
Okay, see you downstairs.
حسنا أراك في الأسفل
Take it.
خذها
Okay, let's go.
حسنا لنذهب
Here's your bill.
خذ القائمة
Okay.
حسنا
Do you have enough money? I have some with me.
هل هذا كافي؟ أنا آخذه هنا
Yes.
نعم
It's settled.
انتهيت
It's not like you to smile at your phone.
تضحك على الهاتف ليس مثلك
Is it a beauty from Qining?
جميلة تشي نينغ
Watch over my mum.
ساعديني في رعاية أمي
I'll pay the bill.
سأذهب لدفع الفاتورة
My dad said
‫قال أبي
Uncle Lu always risked his life on missions.
‫كان العم لو يبذل قصارى جهده في المهمة
He led the team to arrest the culprits
‫يقود الفريق للقبض عليه
for two days and two nights.
قبضنا عليه ليومين وليلتين
After crossing five snow-capped mountains,
‫عبرت خمسة جبل الثلج‬
the claws of police dogs covered with blood,
مخلب الكلاب الشرطة مليء بالدم
he was still chasing after them.
لا يزال يلاحقها
In the end, he caught them.
‫ثم طاردتها
Nobody can get away
‫لا يوجد العم لو
from Uncle Lu.
‫لا يمكن القبض عليه
Once, they went on a mission
في آخر مرة قاموا بتسليم المهمة
at a forbidden zone of life
‫إلى منطقة حراسة الحياة‬
with an elevation of about 5,000 metres.
‫منطقة محرمة الحياة‬
They'd walked a dozen kilometres
‫مشي أكثر من عشرة كيلومترات‬
and carried out the villagers who passed out with oxygen deficiency.
حملت الأصدقاء المفقودين من الأكسجين
The villagers recovered after being carried out,
لا بأس
but some team members had altitude sickness
هناك ردة فعل على السطح العالي في الفريق
and almost died.
كدت أموت
Aunt Gui Xiao.
سيدة جوى شياو
How did you
أنتما
know each other?
كيف تعرفتما؟
We're alumni.
زميل
You're indeed alumni?
إنه زميل في المدرسة
I thought it was an excuse.
‫اعتقدت أنه عذر
His name was Lu Chen at first.
‫كان يدعى لو تشين في البداية
Later, he changed his name by adding Yan in the middle.
‫ثم غيرت اسمه أضفت التهاب
Do you know that?
هل تعرف
No wonder.
لا عجب
That day in the parking lot,
‫في موقف السيارات ذلك اليوم
you called him Lu Chen.
‫ناديني العم لو تشين
I felt weird at that time.
‫أنا غريب بعض الشيء
Although we went to the same school,
بالرغم من أننا زملاء المدرسة
I hadn't met him
لكن في البداية
at first,
لم أره من قبل
but always heard about
‫سمعت دائما
Lu Chen in the 12th grade
‫أن هناك شخص يدعى لو تشين في الصف الثالث
having a good look.
‫وسيم جدا
And then?
وبعد ذلك
That's our business. Kids can't inquire about it.
لا تسأل عن السيد
Xiao.
شياو شياو
This is my cousin, Lu Chen.
‫هذا ابن عمي لو تشين
Lu Yanchen.
‫لو يان تشن
Yes, when he was in school,
‫نعم عندما كنت في المدرسة
he changed his name because it duplicated with others.
عندما كنت في المدرسة
But we still
‫لكن العائلة
call him Lu Chen.
‫لا يزال يناديه لو تشين
Boss, two more.
‫أيها الرئيس أعطني سلتين أخرى
Okay.
حسنا
Hi, Gui Xiao.
ها أنت ذا
Have you done your summer homework?
هل أنهيت واجباتك في العطلة الصيفية
Yet you're hanging out here.
خرجت للعب
Aren't you the same?
ألست كذلك
I'm going to celebrate Meng Xiaoshan and others' graduation.
‫للاحتفال بتخريج منغ شياو شان‬
It's an exceptional case.
‫خاصة‬
Are you coming to celebrate Meng Xiaoshan's birthday,
‫لإحتفال بعيد ميلاد مينغ شياو شان‬
who has just graduated?
حفلة عيد ميلاد
Yes.
نعم
Turn right. The innermost one.
‫انعطف يميناً إلى الأمام‬
Thank you.
شكرا
What are you laughing at?
لماذا تضحك
Believe it or not, I'll pocket all in the next round.
هل تصدقين أنني سآخذ العصا التالية
I don't think so.
لا أعتقد
We have made a bet.
نحن نراهن
Whoever wins will buy the beverages.
من الفائز من سيشتري الماء
Won't he get a heat stroke
ارتدي الكثير
wearing so much?
‫ألن تصاب بالشمس؟
Chen.
‫تشين
Chen, this is Meng Xiaoshan's sister
‫هذه أخت منغ شياو شان
and my sister-in-law, Gui Xiao.
زوجة أخي "غوي شياو"
Game.
!هيا
Let me play in the next game.
سأتولى الجولة التالية
You're even shorter than the cue stick.
أنت لست طويلًا
You'd better just watch them playing.
راقبه جيدا
Didn't you make a block booking?
ألم تحتجز المكان؟
There are no outsiders here. I'm just playing for fun.
لا يوجد الغرباء، أنا ألعب فقط
Yes.
نعم
You've booked for a whole afternoon anyway.
لقد حجزت كل المساء
Just let her play.
دعها تلعب
I'll go get some water.
سأذهب لأحضر الماء
Brother, where are you going?
أخي إلى أين تذهب
I'll play with you for one game.
دعني ألعب معك
You've been sitting here all afternoon.
لقد جلست طوال الظهر
You finally have the mood to exercise.
أخيراً أنت في مزاج جيد للتحرك
I am no match for you.
لا أستطيع هزيمتك
I'll use my left hand.
سأستخدم اليد اليسرى
The rule is who clears the table first, who wins.
من سيفوز بالمنظمة أولاً
In this way, the chances of winning are high.
هذا يعني احتمال الفوز كبير
I'll start the move.
سأفتح
Of course.
‫بالطبع
♫Hi, what day is today?♫
‫لقد سمح لك تشين
How can he not let you start the move?
‫لا يمكنني السماح لك بالكرة أولاً
No way, Chen.
‫تشين
♫Hi, what day is today?♫
‫لا تتنمر علينا هكذا
Gui Xiao.
عائلتنا هي شياو
Yes.
نعم
♫Can I see you?♫
اليوم عيد ميلاد مينغ شياو شان
Why are you bullying her sister?
‫لا تتنمر على أخته
♫Let my heartbeat continue at 110 bpm♫
‫أجل يا تشين
Give in to her.
‫أفسحوا الطريق
He's already using his left hand.
لا تزال تنحى
Why don't you ask Gui Xiao
لماذا لا تدع جوى شياو
to grab the balls and put them directly in the pockets?
رميها بيدك في الحقيبة
Do you want me to take a dive?
هل تريدني أن أتنازل
No.
لا
I'll go and buy something.
سأذهب لشراء بعض الأشياء
It's hot.
ساخن جدا
I forgot to park it in the shade.
نسيت أن أوقف في مكان بارد
Did you burn your butt?
‫أحرقت مؤخرتك
Chen.
‫تشين
Chen, are you leaving?
‫غادر تشين
Later I found out
‫أدركت لاحقاً
something happened to Lu Chen's family
‫في ذلك اليوم قبل امتحان القبول الجامعي
one day before the Gaokao.
‫حدثت مشكلة كبيرة في منزل لو تشين
He didn't settle it until the next afternoon
‫حتى ظهر اليوم التالي
and missed
لقد فاتنا
the first exam in the morning.
الاختبار الأول في الصباح
No one knew
لا أحد يعرف
whether he was going to repeat his final year
هل هو في نهاية المطاف
or work at the repair factory of his family.
أم أخذ مصنع الصيانة في المنزل
Since then,
منذ ذلك الحين
I never saw him again.
لم أره مرة أخرى
Until...
حتى
Sister-in-law, here.
تعالي يا زوجة أخي
I'll treat you to pancakes.
سأدعوك لتناول الكعك
Take it easy.
اعتن بنفسك
Here, the pancake is ready.
‫تفضلي الكعك جاهز
Look how skinny my sister-in-law is.
‫انظر لزوجتي نحيفة جدا‬
Add two eggs for me. Pick the big ones.
بيضتان، اختاري قطعة كبيرة
Okay.
حسنا
Boss, a pancake, please.
‫تفضل كعكة مقلية‬
Okay, please wait a moment.
حسناً لحظة
Come on, handsome, your pancakes.
تعال أيها الوسيم، كعكتك المقلية
Here.
تفضل
Thank you.
شكرا
You're welcome.
على الرحب والسعة
My future bridesmaid.
وصديقتي المستقبلية
My bike.
سيارة
My brother didn't take the Gaokao that day
لم يذهب أخي إلى امتحان القبول الجامعي ذلك اليوم
because he applied for the police academy
بسبب إخفاء والده
without telling his dad.
‫أبلغت مدرسة الشرطة سرا
His dad made a scene before the exam
‫تعرضت لحادث قبل الامتحان
and locked him up in the garage
وأغلق في مصنع السيارة
for two days and three nights.
لمدة يومين وليالي
The first exam was finished by then.
تم الانتهاء من الاختبار الأول
He was released in secret
‫لذا خالتي الثانية
by my aunt after that.
‫أطلقت سراحه سرا
But it was too late.
لكن لا يزال الوقت متأخرًا
Why?
لماذا
Even he applied for the police academy, so what?
ماذا حدث في مدرسة الشرطة
My aunt had divorced my uncle before.
‫خالتي الثانية طلقت مع عمي‬
She married a cop after that.
‫تزوجت شرطياً ثانياً
That cop was very nice.
‫ذلك الشرطي جيد جدا‬
He treated my cousins well.
يعامل ابن عمي وأختي جيدا جدا
But later he got sick and died.
‫لكن بعد ذلك أصيب بالمرض وغادر
My aunt had no income.
‫خالتي الثانية ليس لديها دخل
She couldn't afford to raise two children.
لا تستطيع تربية طفلتين
So she remarried my uncle.
ثم تزوجت مع عمي مرة أخرى
Probably because of jealousy.
ربما بسبب الغيرة
I heard it from my mum.
سمعت من أمي
When my uncle
عمي
knew my cousin had applied for the police academy,
عرفت أن ابن عمي اتصل بمدرسة الشرطة
he went crazy.
فقد جن جنونه
He must have recalled
ربما تذكرت
my aunt's second marriage.
أمر زواج خالتي الثانية
You can never ask
لا تسأل ابن عمي
We don't talk much.
لا أتحدث معه كثيرا
Really?
حقًا؟
I thought you were close
اعتقدت أنكما مقربان
because of Meng Xiaoshan.
‫لأن منغ شياو شان‬
Gui Xiao. I'll wait for you at the school gate.
جوى شياو أنتظرك عند بوابة المدرسة
It's my brother's birthday today.
اليوم عيد ميلاد أخي
Do I need to buy a gift?
هل أحتاج إلى شراء هدية؟
Come on.
‏كفى‏
You bought plush toys
أي زميل في صفنا يحفل بعيد ميلاده
for every student in our class on their birthdays.
‫اشتريت لعبة ريش للآخرين
You've almost
تلك الغرفة المميزة
hollowed out the shop.
كدت أموت
Meng asked you to go empty-handed.
قالت الأخت منغ أن تذهب اليد فارغة
Okay. Wait for me.
حسنا انتظريني
I'll hand in the paper.
‏سأسلم الامتحان‏
He must be there on Haidong's birthday.
‫عيد ميلاد هاي دونغ، يجب أن يكون هنا
This is the factory of Chen's family.
‫هذا مصنع تشين
But customers usually don't come here.
‫لكن الزبائن عادةً لا يأتون إلى هنا
They have to go to the storefront if they need the repairs.
‫يجب أن يتم إصلاحها إلى الباب
Chen.
‫تشين
You're here.
‫أنا قادم
Sit here.
اجلس هنا
Gui Xiao.
‏(مي شياو)‏
Let me introduce them.
دعني أقدم لكم
These are my old classmates.
هؤلاء زملائي القدامى
This is Meng Xiaoshan's sister.
‫هذه أخت منغ شياو شان‬
Her name is Gui Xiao.
اسمها جوى شياو
This is my younger brother, Hai Jianfeng.
هذا أخي هاي جيان فينج
They are our own people.
‫كلنا
Lu Chen's room is too cold.
‫لو تشين، الغرفة باردة جداً
Put it on.
‫ارتديه
You guys are still in high school.
أنتم لا تزالون في المدرسة الثانوية
You can't drink.
لا يمكنك الشرب
Don't worry. I won't let them drink.
لا تقلق لن أدعهم يشربون
This should be where he lives.
يجب أن يكون هذا المكان الذي يعيش فيه
Is this
هل هذا
Hai Jianfeng's best friend?
صديق هاي جيان فينج؟
No, no.
لا لا
This is my sister.
هذه أختي
He's no match for Gui Xiao.
هذا الصبي الأحمق ليس أفضل من "غوي شياو"
I'm serious.
أنا جاد
My sister not only has good grades
إن أداء أختي ممتاز
but also is talented in sports
إنها طالبة مميزة
and is a member of the school choir.
وفريق الغناء الجماعي
She is definitely
بالتأكيد
the favourite of all teachers.
لحم الأساتذة المختلفة
A straight-A student? Not bad.
طالبة متفوقة   جيد
Are there enough dishes?
هل الأطباق كافية؟
No.
لا يكفي
I want to eat pickled cabbage with vinegar sauce.
أريد أكل هذا الملفوف المقلي
One more.
مرة أخرى
Coming.
‫هيا‬
Good.
جيد
Try it.
تذوق
Chen.
‫تشين
Your cooking is so good.
‫أنت ماهر جداً
Of course.
بالطبع
You don't have to rush back, right?
لا تستعجل للعودة
It's my birthday today.
اليوم عيد ميلادي
We finally get together.
لم يكن من السهل أن نجتمع
Otherwise,
وإلا
I don't dare to waste your study time.
لا أجرؤ على إضاعة وقتك في الدراسة
No hurry.
لا تستعجلي
It's Friday.
اليوم الجمعة
Okay, that's good.
‫حسناً هذا جيد
Try it. Lu Chen is good at cooking.
‫جرب  لو تشين ماهر في الطبخ